<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Gabriele Sarti</title>
    <link>https://gsarti.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gsarti.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Gabriele Sarti 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gsarti.com/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributing Context Usage in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/pecore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/pecore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PECoRe is a framework using the internal properties of generative language models to identify and attribute context usage in their generations. In particular, the framework is composed by two steps: Context-sensitive Token Identification (CTI), where generated tokens are classified as context-sensitive by contrastively comparing their probabilities with and without context, and Contextual Cues Imputation (CCI), where the dependence of token selected in the CTI step is highlighted by using contrastive attribution. The framework is integrated in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/inseq-team/inseq&#34;&gt;Inseq interpretability library&lt;/a&gt; and can be easily used thanks to the &lt;code&gt;inseq attribute-context&lt;/code&gt; command. The framework is described in detail in the paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://gsarti.com/publication/pecore/&#34;&gt;Quantifying the Plausibility of Context Reliance in Neural Machine Translation&lt;/a&gt;, published at ICLR 2024, and its extension MIRAGE was created to support answer attribution in RAG applications &lt;a href=&#34;https://gsarti.com/publication/mirage/&#34;&gt;Model Internals-based Answer Attribution for Trustworthy Retrieval-Augmented Generation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inseq: An Interpretability Toolkit for Sequence Generation Models</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/inseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/inseq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inseq is a Pytorch-based hackable toolkit to democratize the study of interpretability for sequence generation models. Inseq supports a wide set of models from the 🤗 Transformers library and an ever-growing set of feature attribution methods, leveraging in part the widely-used Captum library. For a quick introduction to common use cases, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://inseq.readthedocs.io/examples/quickstart.html&#34;&gt;Getting started with Inseq&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Inseq, feature attribution maps that can be saved, reloaded, aggregated and visualized either as HTMLs (with Jupyter notebook support) or directly in the console using rich. Besides simple attribution, Inseq also supports features like step score extraction, attribution aggregation and attributed functions customization for more advanced use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrastive Image-Text Pretraining for Italian</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/clip-italian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/clip-italian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CLIP is a multimodel model that can learn to represent images and text jointly in the same space. In this project, we aim to propose the first CLIP model trained on Italian data, that in this context can be considered a low resource language. Using a few techniques, we have been able to fine-tune a SOTA Italian CLIP model with only 1.4 million training samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/spaces/clip-italian/clip-italian-demo&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Semantic Browser</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/covid-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/covid-browser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2020, more than 3,000 scientific studies have been published on the SARS-CoV-2 virus and on the Covid-19 pathology. The total number of articles on the topic of coronaviruses exceeds 40,000 units. Such a volume of scientific production makes it impossible for doctors and researchers to keep up with the latest discoveries without the support of adequate digital platforms that are currently nowhere in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make up for this shortcoming, we propose an artificial intelligence system associated with a web application to perform natural language semantic querying inside the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.semanticscholar.org/coronavirus-research&#34;&gt;COVID-19 Open Research Dataset&lt;/a&gt; published by the American nonprofit &lt;a href=&#34;https://allenai.org/&#34;&gt;AllenAI&lt;/a&gt;. The system leverages state-of-the-art neural language models trained on scientific publications in the biomedical domain for optimal retrieval performances. The adoption of the system aims to facilitate knowledge sharing across the scientific community and to accelerate the development of adequate drugs and vaccines to counter the ongoing pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is led by Gabriele Sarti in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;en.areasciencepark.it&#34;&gt;Area Science Park&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;ai-lc.it&#34;&gt;Italian Association of Computational Linguistics&lt;/a&gt;. The project used to be publicly available at covidbrowser.areasciencepark.it. You can now refer to the code implementation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gsarti/covid-papers-browser&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AItalo Svevo: Letters from an Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/aitalo-svevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/aitalo-svevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed an interactive experience putting together NLP and literature to raise awareness on the latest developments in language modeling and natural language generation. Participants received a printed letter written by a neural language model (GPT-2) fine-tuned on the Italian epistolary corpus of Italo Svevo, an italian writer of the 20th century. Participants could choose among several topics discussed by the author in his letters, and were also given some context on author&amp;rsquo;s life and literary production by Cristina Fenu, a digital humanist working at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.museosveviano.it/ar/progetto/archivio-digitale/&#34;&gt;Svevian Museum of Trieste&lt;/a&gt;. An open-source implementation will soon be available on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histopathologic Cancer Detection with Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gsarti.com/project/cancer-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gsarti.com/project/cancer-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As our final project for the course of Statistical Machine Learning held by Prof. Luca Bortolussi we explored different statistical and deep approaches to the problem of detecting tumors in histopathologic scans. We notably tried a random forest on distributional features extracted by pigment segmentation, a state-of-the-art DenseNet and a Capsule Network with Dynamic Routing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
